<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Alfredo Design</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1314/categories/blogs/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>en</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 12:09:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>My alternative solution for reverting the mouse zooming scroll direction when switching between Figma and Adobe XD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1314/post/2022/05/01/my-alternative-solution-for-reverting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 12:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1314/post/2022/05/01/my-alternative-solution-for-reverting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use Adobe XD regularly for my full-time job, while Figma is my go-to for personal projects. Consequently, I&#39;m eternally oscillating between these two apps on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent the whole day on Adobe XD, transitioning to Figma is somewhat peculiar due to the contrasting scrolling direction for zoom-in and zoom-out operations. Although neither direction seems inherently correct or incorrect, for some reason, Figma&#39;s method appears more intuitive to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after a &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.adobe.com/t5/adobe-xd-discussions/mouse-zooming-scroll-direction-is-reversed/td-p/11513112&#34;&gt;much extensive search&lt;/a&gt; for a solution, it was disheartening to discover that neither of the applications offers the option to customize the zoom scrolling direction. The sole work-around I could find was to alternately enable or disable the scrolling direction on my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;shadow-lg aligncenter wp-image-3417 size-full&#34; src=&#34;https://alfredo.design/uploads/2025/b686615707.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1148&#34; height=&#34;885&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But going to &#34;Preferences &gt; Mouse settings&#34; every time I needed to make the switch was a tedious process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While wishing there was a quicker way to switch the mouse scrolling direction on my mac, I did some research and I found a tool called: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ther0n/UnnaturalScrollWheels&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UnnaturalScrollWheels&lt;/a&gt; which exists as a solution for those who want to set the natural scrolling direction on the trackpad while maintaining the regular scrolling direction on the mouse. (Because for some reason, when toggling the &#34;Scroll direction: Natural&#34; option on a mac, it also changes the Trackpad scrolling direction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this tool installed, now I simply click the icon on the menu bar &gt; Preferences and check or uncheck the invert vertical scrolling every time I switch from AdobeXD to Figma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-3415 size-full aligncenter&#34; src=&#34;https://alfredo.design/uploads/2025/436c012fa3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;401&#34; height=&#34;380&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is found useful for those UX designers, who like me, are constantly using both apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>